you can grow a disembodied human brain
from a stem cell and have it operate a
robot I told you guys that the US
military had been studying this since at
least 2012 and people said they must
have had it a decade earlier and they
definitely did I bring you the very
first brain operated robot this was a
robot that was made in 2008 using rat
brain organoids they gave it the ability
to operate an autonomous robot of course
now we put them in spider drones human
brains are for more complex than any
other kind of brain we know of so it
makes sense if we wanted a really smart
robot we would want to use human brains
to do it and we can indeed combine them
with AI now we have known that you can
immerse disembodied brains in Game World
for a scary long time starting in 2001
in the publication database I don't
think brain controlled robots went very
far because they just aren't that smart
but it wasn't until AI got really scary
good that we had the ability to make
them smarter AI is so so powerful but
what it lacks is creativity having
biological AI could bridge that Gap and
we know they're good at it we know
they're better at learning than even our
best AI models there are three different
ways that we can train the little
organoids we can provide them with
reinforcement learning and that's what
they're using for the computation
subscription model where they get a
benefit for performing the correct
activity and they get a punishment for
not we can do unsupervised learning and
that's what they used to teach them
language or they can communicate with AI
and they're able to learn just because
they're enjoying it for lack of a better
term they're learning and it makes sense
then there's the really powerful
supervised learning where we can take
what they start to understand and then
provide them more of that and it's
directed at what kind of task we want
them to do for the ones that you can
presently rent out to do computation and
by the way I I want to run them on a
large language model so bad I want to
talk to a brain organoid they have a
method of teaching them where when they
do the correct task they get a little
jolt of dopamine in fact the spikes in
the brain activity will activate this
little dopamine release mechanism this
is actually a form of addiction they are
addicted to learning to solve our
problems for us this is actually what
they look like and for their model when
they stop giving electrical activity and
stop putting output then they assume
that that brain organoid probably is no
longer alive so they can replace them
but fortunately since they're to a chip
the other ones have still learned to do
the task and they can pick up with them
as for the ethical thing to do when they
do reach Consciousness some have
suggested the same outcome that we could
do for AI humanely terminate them